SERGEI STAROV

Oakland, CA • C: (702) 572-7335 • E: <u>starovdev@gmail.com</u>

• https://starovsergei.github.io/personal-page/

SUMMARY

Professional Software Development Engineer in Test with over 7 years of experience in software development, web, mobile automation and managing QA teams. I have hired and managed cross-border, cross-functional QA talent in US and India to deliver best-in-class product experience with full range of testing across all levels of test pyramid (from functional, UI, integration to unit tests)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, JavaScript, React, Java, HTML & CSS, Ruby, C/C++

Automation: Selenium WebDriver, Cypress, Postman, Jasmine, Jest, Mocha,

Jenkins, TestNG, JUnit, Maven, Appium, Gradle, Sauce Labs, Git

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TestPro, Sunnyvale, CA Software Automation Engineer

January 2020 – present

- Developed Test Automation framework for UI testing from scratch using Python, Selenium WebDriver, Jenkins, Sauce Labs
- Created test strategies and set up infrastructure test automation for web and mobile platforms.
- Own end-to-end QA process, black, grey and white box testing methodologies and mentoring
- Mentoring junior QA engineers.

Auto Club of Southern California (AAA), Los Angeles, CA Software Engineer February 2018 – January 2020

- Developed applications for online insurance products exclude/remove/add drivers from auto insurance policy with React, Javascript, Typescript used by hundreds of thousands customers.
- Developed and maintained unit tests using Jasmine, Jest, Mocha frameworks following TDD practices and mock testing techniques
- Evaluated applications' code in compliance with OWASP security practices and eliminated vulnerabilities

- Built QA team by leading the hiring, training process and managing both onsite and offshore teams
- Created automation test suites for UI and RESTful services using Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, TestRail and Java, automation solutions for CI/CD process with Jenkins, Maven, Selenium Grid, AWS. As a result, time to verify new builds/releases has been significantly reduced (up to 80%).
- Developed efficient and secure internal tool for back-end API testing (integration testing)
- Developed and maintained application for performance/load testing of company servers.

CreativeDrive, Hollywood, FL Software Automation Engineer

August 2015 – April 2016

- Created more than 300 automated scripts for testing CreativeDrive asset management release software using Selenium WebDriver, Java and JUnit
- Work with technical leads from development and DevOps on the overall test automation ecosystem across engineering practice with effective CI/CD strategies
- Worked closely with Dev, PM teams in an agile setting with two weeks sprint planning, retrospective and daily standups.

EDUCATION

BA in Legal Studies, Herzen State University, St. Petersburg, Russia	2010-2014
Computer Science Certificate, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL	2016-2017
Computer Programming Extension, University of California Santa Cruz, CA	2020-2021